var quiz = { "JS" : [
	{
		"id" : 1,
		"question" : "In Python 3,the maximum value for an integer is 2**63 -1 is",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "False", 
			 "b":"True" 
			 }
			],
		"answer":"False",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 2,
		"question" : "What is a correct syntax to output 'Hello World' in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "print('Hello World')", 
			 "b":"echo('Hello World');", 
			 "c":"p('Hello World')",
			 "d":"echo 'Hello World'"
			}
			],
		"answer":"print('Hello World')",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 3,
		"question" : "How do you insert COMMENTS in Python code?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "#This is a comment", 
			 "b":"/*This is a comment*/", 
			 "c":"//This is a comment"
			}
			],
		"answer":"#This is a comment",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 4,
		"question" : "Which one is NOT a legal variable name?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Myvar", 
			 "b":"my_var",
			 "c":"my-var",
			 "d":"_myvar"
			}
			],
		"answer":"my-var",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 5,
		"question" : "How do you create a variable with the numeric value 5?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "x = 5", 
			 "b":"Both the other answers are correct",
			 "c":"x = int(5)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Both the other answers are correct",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 6,
		"question" : "What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": ".py", 
			 "b":".pyth",
			 "c":".pt",
			 "d":".pyt"
			}
			],
		"answer":".py",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 7,
		"question" : "How do you create a variable with the floating number 2.8?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "x = 2.8", 
			 "b":"x = float(2.8)",
			 "c":"Both the answers are correct",
			}
			],
		"answer":"Both the answers are correct",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 8,
		"question" : "What is the correct syntax to output the type of a variable or object in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "print(type(x))", 
			 "b":"print(typeof(x))",
			 "c":"print(typeof x)",
			 "d":"print(typeOf(x))",
			}
			],
		"answer":"print(type(x))",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 9,
		"question" : "What is the correct way to create a function in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "function myfunction():", 
			 "b":"def myFunction():",
			 "c":"create myFunction():",
			}
			],
		"answer":"def myFunction():",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 10,
		"question" : "In Python, 'Hello', is the same as Hello",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "True", 
			 "b":"False",
			}
			],
		"answer":"False",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 11,
		"question" : "What is a correct syntax to return the first character in a string?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "x = sub('Hello', 0, 1)", 
			 "b":"x = 'Hello'[0]",
			 "c":"x= 'Hello' sub(0, 1)"
			}
			],
		"answer":"'Hello'[0]",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 12,
		"question" : "Which method can be used to remove any whitespace from both the beginning and the end of a string?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "trim()", 
			 "b":"ptrim()",
			 "c":"strip()",
			 "d":"len()"
			}
			],
		"answer":"strip()",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 13,
		"question" : "Which method can be used to return a string in upper case letters?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "uppercase()", 
			 "b":"upperCase()",
			 "c":"upper()",
			 "d":"toUpperCase()"
			}
			],
		"answer":"upper()",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 14,
		"question" : "Which method can be used to replace parts of a string?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "replaceString()", 
			 "b":"replace()",
			 "c":"repl()",
			 "d":"switch()"
			}
			],
		"answer":"replace()",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 15,
		"question" : "WhWhich operator is used to multiply numbers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "%", 
			 "b":"*",
			 "c":"#",
			 "d":"x"
			}
			],
		"answer":"*",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 16,
		"question" : "Which operator can be used to compare two values?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "<>", 
			 "b":"==",
			 "c":"=",
			 "d":"><"
			}
			],
		"answer":"==",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 17,
		"question" : "Which of these collections defines a LIST?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')", 
			 "b":"['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']",
			 "c":"('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')",
			 "d":"{'name': 'apple', 'color': 'green'}"
			}
			],
		"answer":"['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 18,
		"question" : "Which of these collections defines a TUPLE?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')", 
			 "b":"['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']",
			 "c":"('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')",
			 "d":"{'name': 'apple', 'color': 'green'}"
			}
			],
		"answer":"('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 19,
		"question" : "Which of these collections defines a SET?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')", 
			 "b":"['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']",
			 "c":"('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')",
			 "d":"{'name': 'apple', 'color': 'green'}"
			}
			],
		"answer":"{'apple', 'banana', 'cherry'}",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 20,
		"question" : "Which of these collections defines a DICTIONARY?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')", 
			 "b":"['apple', 'banana', 'cherry']",
			 "c":"('apple', 'banana', 'cherry')",
			 "d":"{'name': 'apple', 'color': 'green'}"
			}
			],
		"answer":"{'name': 'apple','color': 'green'}",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 21,
		"question" : "Which collection is ordered, changeable, and allows duplicate members?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "TUPLE", 
			 "b":"DICTIONARY",
			 "c":"LIST",
			 "d":"SET"
			}
			],
		"answer":"LIST",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 22,
		"question" : "Which collection does not allow duplicate members?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "TUPLE", 
			 "b":"SET",
			 "c":"LIST"
			}
			],
		"answer":"SET",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 23,
		"question" : "How do you start writing an if statement in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "if x > y:", 
			 "b":"if x > y then:",
			 "c":"if (x > y) "
			}
			],
		"answer":"if x > y:",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 24,
		"question" : "How do you start writing a while loop in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "while x > y {", 
			 "b":"x > y while {",
			 "c":"while (x > y)",
			 "d":"while x > y:"
			}
			],
		"answer":"while x > y:",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 25,
		"question" : "How do you start writing a for loop in Python?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "for x > y:", 
			 "b":"for x in y:",
			 "c":"for each x in y:"
			}
			],
		"answer":"for x > y:",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	}
	]
}



var quizApp = function() {

	this.score = 0;		
	this.qno = 1;
	this.currentque = 0;
	var totalque = quiz.JS.length;

	
	this.displayQuiz = function(cque) {
		this.currentque = cque;
		if(this.currentque <  totalque) {
			$("#tque").html(totalque);
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#next").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
	
			
			$("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);	
			 $("#question-options").html("");
			for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
			  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
		
				$("#question-options").append(
					"<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
					"<label class='form-check-label'>" +
							  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option'   id='q"+key+"' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
								  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
							 "</span></label>"
				);
			  }
			}
		}
		if(this.currentque <= 0) {
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", true);	
		}
		if(this.currentque >= totalque) {
				$('#next').attr('disabled', true);
				for(var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
					this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
				}
			return this.showResult(this.score);	
		}
	}
	
	this.showResult = function(scr) {
		$("#result").addClass('result');
		$("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr  + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
		for(var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
			var res;
			if(quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
					res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
			} else {
				res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
			}
			$("#result").append(
			'<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
			'<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
			'<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
			
			'</div>' 
			
			);
			
		}
	}
	
	this.checkAnswer = function(option) {
		var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
		option = option.replace(/\</g,"&lt;")   //for <
		option = option.replace(/\>/g,"&gt;")   //for >
		option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")

		if(option ==  quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
			if(quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
		}
		} else {
			quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
		}
		
	}	
	 
	this.changeQuestion = function(cque) {
			this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
			this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);	
			
	}
	
}


var jsq = new quizApp();

var selectedopt;
	$(document).ready(function() {
			jsq.displayQuiz(0);		
		
	$('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function(e) {

			//var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
			$(this).prop("checked", true);
				selectedopt = $(this).val();
		});
		
			
			 
	});

	
	
	
	$('#next').click(function(e) {
			e.preventDefault();
			if(selectedopt) {
				jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
			}
			jsq.changeQuestion(1);
	});	
	
	$('#previous').click(function(e) {
		e.preventDefault();
		if(selectedopt) {
			jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
		}
			jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
	});	



